[{"id": "5e38ce17f6c8a670a7957c52", "question": "What is Jean Valjean's prison number in the novel \"Les Miserables\"?", "answer": "24601", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5990f510fa5fdd6dd25324eb", "question": "Central African Republic gaines its independence from which European country in 1960?", "answer": "France", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5a162cd9f01ec323f8491733", "question": "Tradionally, what does a Fletcher make?", "answer": "Arrows", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8bc", "question": "What is the more common name for Tympanum?", "answer": "Eardrum", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133936a", "question": "What was Indiana Jones' dad afraid of in the movie \"Indiana Jones and The Last Crusade\"?", "answer": "Rats", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ce3", "question": "What 1838 Charles Dickens novel is subtitled \"The Parish Boy's Progress\"?", "answer": "Oliver Twist", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5bbd49cd00d154d7af00b8cb", "question": "What year did Nirvana frontman, Kurt Cobain, die?", "answer": "1994", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5feb34337e83c707845b20c8", "question": "Russia is the world\u2019s largest country (by area), and its largest city (by population) is its capital. What\u2019s the next \u00adlargest country for which this is the case?", "answer": "Argentina", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "591c3788815febcc896f9271", "question": "How many feet are there in a fathom?", "answer": "Six", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133affe", "question": "After defeating Martin Van Buren, who died of pneumonia shortly after taking office?", "answer": "William Henry Harrison", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b475", "question": "When was the tire company, Michelin, founded?", "answer": "1889", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a94", "question": "Who had a flying carpet?", "answer": "Aladdin", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ab99c4821a8909e5c332d34", "question": "Who played Franz Liszt in the 1975 film \"Lisztomania\"?", "answer": "Roger Daltrey", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339108", "question": "Who wrote the book \"Man's Search for Meaning\"?", "answer": "Viktor E. Frankl", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b81c", "question": "What color blazer is presented to the Masters golf winner?", "answer": "Green", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133adac", "question": "Who was Araminta Ross known as?", "answer": "Harriet Tubman", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391af", "question": "Who dramatically kissed Halle Berry on stage when he won Best Actor?", "answer": "Adrien Brody", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd81", "question": "With what team did Dennis Rodman win his first NBA title?", "answer": "The Detroit Pistons", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b507", "question": "What is tripe on a menu?", "answer": "Stomach", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ae8637d7f28483af1e7fdca", "question": "What country would you find Mount Elbrus in?", "answer": "Russia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391e4", "question": "Whose memory is the movie \"Gladiator\" dedicated to?", "answer": "Oliver Reed's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "60173fcf44491cbd7c5a17b6", "question": "What is the name of the pagan festival that used to be held during the same period as Valentine's Day?", "answer": "Lupercalia was a festival dedicated to Faunus, the Roman god of agriculture. It was held the middle of February.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6a3", "question": "Which state is located on the northern border of Pennsylvania?", "answer": "New York", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388ae", "question": "How many ghosts appear to Scrooge in Dicken's \"A Christmas Carol\"?", "answer": "Four", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9e5", "question": "How much storage space did the original Amazon Kindle device have?", "answer": "256 MB", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58b36f991c3f17ccc40c8e0f", "question": "Who plays the role of Haley Joel Osment\u2019s mother in the film \"The Sixth Sense\"?", "answer": "Toni Collette", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff51487ff04d658268c92e3", "question": "What Spartan king led a small army of 300 Spartans against a vastly superior Persian force in the Battle of Thermopylae?", "answer": "Leonidas, King of Sparta", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fecdb4dec223966ae8f88f2", "question": "In \"Ghostbusters,\" what prompts Dr. Peter Venkman to say, \"Well, there's something you don't see every day\"?", "answer": "Stay Puft Marshmallow Man", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b169", "question": "What was the name of the site used to build the Empire State Building?", "answer": "John Thompson Farm", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b35", "question": "In 1976, who was the first woman to become a national network news co-anchor?", "answer": "Barbara Walters", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5febaad87e83c707845b20e2", "question": "Who created the centigrade scale, which was later renamed in his honor?", "answer": "Anders Celsius", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe52f931bf59ab7d2e38116", "question": "How many spikes are on the Statue of Liberty's crown?", "answer": "7", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58bb342be368446ca7bd684a", "question": "What year was the instant coffee, Nescafe, released onto the market?", "answer": "1938", "category": "general"}, {"id": "600242dc4be4723ccac2218e", "question": "Which war novel follows the life of Captain John Yossarian?", "answer": "\"Catch-22\"", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338dc7", "question": "Whose sidekick was named Sancho Panza?", "answer": "Don Quixote", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a959", "question": "Which European country replaced the Schilling with the Euro?", "answer": "Austria", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4b1", "question": "In what non-Spanish-speaking city would you find the Spanish Steps?", "answer": "Rome", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6015f86cfe83fe1f2a824c2d", "question": "Passover is celebrated around the same time with a Christian holiday. What Christian holiday is this?", "answer": "Easter Passover is usually celebrated in March or April, which is around the same time Christians also celebrate Easter.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fea3893ff048f679a45ab25", "question": "What color catches the eye first?", "answer": "Yellow", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3dc", "question": "Which famous piece of artwork depicts the \"Battle of Hastings\"?", "answer": "Bayeux Tapestry", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a486", "question": "Mount Etna is located on which island?", "answer": "Sicily", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac53", "question": "What did woman use to redden their lips during the era of Louis XIV?", "answer": "Lemons", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338bbc", "question": "Who was the twin brother of Artemis?", "answer": "Apollo", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5902a066cad1ec93f27df76a", "question": "Which Bohemian city gave us the Pilsner?", "answer": "Pilsen", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fef92cd6ce05a3942286e87", "question": "Which famous actor was orginally offered the role of Tommy Williams in the movie \"The Shawshank Redemption\"?", "answer": "Brad Pitt", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fecd1e4ec223966ae8f88c1", "question": "While filming \"Guardians of the Galaxy\", what did director James Gunn give out as rewards to his actors and crew?", "answer": "Play-Doh", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c33e", "question": "How long does it take the moon to revolve around the Earth, to the nearest day?", "answer": "27", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339dae", "question": "In what 2006 film did Sebastian Foucan, the inventor of \"free running\", show off his sport?", "answer": "Casino Royale", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0bc", "question": "What pseudonym was Norma McCorvey given in a historic 1973 Supreme Court ruling?", "answer": "Jane Roe", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca8b", "question": "What element do you need to avoid goitre?", "answer": "Iodine", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a71d", "question": "Which US state is nickname the \"Bluegrass State\"?", "answer": "Kentucky", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe8b1cc01dd7bf43be5e795", "question": "What is someone who is \"making a mountain out of a molehill\" doing?", "answer": "Exaggerating a minor problem", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba2b", "question": "In which US state is the General Sherman Tree located?", "answer": "California", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58ec22f68dc25ca9e12ef62b", "question": "As whom was J\u00e1n Ludv\u00edk Hyman Binyamin Hoch better known?", "answer": "Robert Maxwell", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcfd", "question": "What term for stable, well-established stocks comes from a $10 bet in poker?", "answer": "Blue chips", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca57", "question": "Christopher Cockerell is best known for invented what?", "answer": "The hovercraft", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe69f1720565ad31a57c78a", "question": "The first woman to run for president chose whom as her running mate?", "answer": "Fredrick Douglas", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133acb7", "question": "How many main islands make up the state of Hawaii?", "answer": "Eight", "category": "history"}, {"id": "590722383745b36be73039fd", "question": "What international company is said to have influenced the image of the modern-day Santa Claus?", "answer": "Coca-Cola", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fea3e9eff048f679a45ab5c", "question": "High blood pressure is also known as what?", "answer": "Hypertension", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1f1", "question": "What year did Volkswagen debut the Golf?", "answer": "1974", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133992b", "question": "Which one of opera\u2019s \"Three Tenor\u2019s\" names translates in English as \"Quiet Sunday\"?", "answer": "Placido Domingo", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338881", "question": "What adventure tale introduced: \"Yo-ho-ho, and a bottle of rum!\"", "answer": "Treasure Island", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe8f28401dd7bf43be5e80f", "question": "What is the whiskey that evaporates from its barrel called?", "answer": "Angel's share", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c12d", "question": "Live Aid was organized to benefit which starving country?\u00a0", "answer": "Ethiopia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd96fae23c87fd04dd15e44", "question": "Which Christmas song was actually written for Thanksgiving?", "answer": "\"Jingle Bells\"", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c91c", "question": "This protein makes the blood red in color?", "answer": "Hemoglobin", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e27", "question": "What began as a ligature of the letters \"e\" and \"t\"?", "answer": "The ampersand", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d9f", "question": "What author created the character of Tom Buchanan?", "answer": "F. Scott Fitzgerald", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "58f564b533a95c66dc4fe751", "question": "Who played the character of Evelyn Mulwray in the 1974 film \"Chinatown\"?", "answer": "Faye Dunaway", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b349", "question": "Who was the first woman to sail single-handed around the world?", "answer": "Naomi James", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59e802f7de59ea584496fe9a", "question": "Which fashion designer is popular for his \"Space Age\" look?", "answer": "Pierre Cardin", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5c90d55952800b05cac20f1d", "question": "During what geological time period did the T-Rex roam the Earth?", "answer": "Cretaceous Period", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c06d", "question": "In what decade was Montreal Canadien great Maurice \"Rocket\" Richard born?", "answer": "1920s", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca50", "question": "Honeydew is a variety of what?", "answer": "Melon", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59cdb20f65ff7d326b622a70", "question": "What is the study of rocks and their formation called?", "answer": "Petrology", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b694", "question": "Candy Lightner was the founder of what organization?", "answer": "Mothers Against Drunk Driving", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe12ca3e39efa6330e0fec7", "question": "In what state is the oldest winery in the United States?", "answer": "New York", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0b6", "question": "Who did Abraham Lincoln face in a series of debates in 1858?", "answer": "Stephen Douglas", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fecdb56ec223966ae8f88f3", "question": "In \"Die Hard,\" how does John McClane signal officer Powell that something is wrong at Nakatomi Plaza?", "answer": "Drops a dead body on his car", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fefc3096ce05a3942286f1c", "question": "In the film \"The Usual Suspects,\" Roger \"Verbal\" Kint supposedly suffers from what ailment?", "answer": "Cerebral palsy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59e6bd30fb6c85e9e634ff64", "question": "Who won the World Series in 1987?", "answer": "Minnesota Twins", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d9b", "question": "What author created the character of Tom Marvolo Riddle?", "answer": "J. K. Rowling", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59f9baa1364247bf200fb89a", "question": "What is the fear of death known as?", "answer": "Necrophobia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339226", "question": "What country provided most of the settings for \"The Lord of the Rings\" movies?", "answer": "New Zealand", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd2cf712596a59cbdfbd36f", "question": "Potassium Nitrate is also known as what?", "answer": "Saltpeter", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b308", "question": "Who received a speeding ticket while driving his Porsche Spyder on September 30, 1955?", "answer": "James Dean", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abf9", "question": "What country is the Mekong Delta located in?", "answer": "Vietnam", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ae8604c4007905755f79e8e", "question": "What countries make up the United Kingdom?", "answer": "England, Wales, Scotland, and Northern Ireland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5feddbac6ce05a3942286d92", "question": "What does the yellow, red and blue stand for in the Steelers logo?", "answer": "Coal, Ore and Steel Scrap", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6df", "question": "What US territory includes the islands of Saint Croix, Saint John and Saint Thomas?", "answer": "US Virgin Islands", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c498", "question": "Which English philosopher believed that people in a state of nature are violent?", "answer": "Thomas Hobbes", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8c4", "question": "What is the Japanese alcoholic drink sake made from?", "answer": "Rice", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3c8", "question": "When was US President James Garfield shot and killed?", "answer": "July 2, 1881", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5ca", "question": "Who created the operating system \"Linux\"?", "answer": "Linus Torvalds", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a89", "question": "According to legend, Robin Hood was born in what area of Nottinghamshire?", "answer": "Locksley", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a055", "question": "What 1977 film directed by and starring Ron Howard shares its name with a video game series?", "answer": "Grand Theft Auto", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5909d089bb53d1af658864fc", "question": "What year did the Trans-Siberian Orchestra release their debut album entitled \"Christmas Eve and Other Stories\"?", "answer": "1996", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5b174565bb2d29f81593b701", "question": "Who was the lead singer of the British-American rock band \"Foreigner\"?", "answer": "Lou Gramm", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58dba63b874c93a3298b2157", "question": "In the film \"Men In Black 3\", what did Agent K like to eat in order to think better?", "answer": "Pie", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a9e970a7ccba3ffe45786f6", "question": "What is the fear of bees known as?", "answer": "Melissophobia", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a13f", "question": "\"Safety Dance\" was a hit for which band?", "answer": "Men Without Hats", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bb86", "question": "What South African golfer is nicknamed \"The Big Easy\"?", "answer": "Ernie Els", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a044", "question": "What alien did Ben 10 first turn into in \"Ben 10: Alien Force\"?", "answer": "Swampfire", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd0e", "question": "What was the original brand of cereal whose mascot was Cornelius?", "answer": "Kellogg's Corn Flakes", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b71d", "question": "Who eats Christpsomo when they return home from mass at 4 a.m. Christmas morning?", "answer": "Greek Christians", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ad7e6dcb24f84e0b9f9ffb4", "question": "In computing, what is \"Hypertext Transfer Protocol\" typically abbreviated to?", "answer": "HTTP", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c60b", "question": "What is the fear of washing or bathing called?", "answer": "Ablutophobia", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5b2", "question": "How many rings are there on a five-zone archery target?", "answer": "Four", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b509", "question": "What two months are named for men?", "answer": "July and August", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac79", "question": "During which American period did stock car racing gain most of its popularity?", "answer": "The Prohibition", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fefa8ce6ce05a3942286ed7", "question": "Who played the part of Max Cady in the 1991 thriller \"Cape Fear\"?", "answer": "Robert De Niro", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b027", "question": "Who was the 36th US President?", "answer": "Lyndon Johnson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4be", "question": "When did the Seychelles gain their independence from the United Kingdom?", "answer": "June 29, 1975", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5937eb0e08d98002fdd633ab", "question": "Who created the children's land of Narnia?", "answer": "C. S. Lewis", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa96", "question": "In what country is Thunder Bay?", "answer": "Canada", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "596dfd319616e6c6d4eba4f4", "question": "What is a baby swan called?", "answer": "A Cygnet", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396fc", "question": "Who was the King of Swing?", "answer": "Benny Goodman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d8e", "question": "What original literary work was the movie \"Christmas with the Kranks\" based on?", "answer": "Skipping Christmas", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5feccfbbec223966ae8f88b8", "question": "What was Cecil B. DeMille's first film to be nominated for the Academy Award for Best Picture?", "answer": "\"Cleopatra\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8ce", "question": "What do the thirteen stripes on the American flag represent?", "answer": "The thirteen original colonies", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6ad", "question": "Samhainophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Halloween", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fb083c6cf631c2414a13b48", "question": "What is meteorology the study of?", "answer": "Weather Forecasting", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58d06c78870e6f05ba600853", "question": "As the speed of a body approaches the speed of light, its mass approaches what?", "answer": "Infinity", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59008e89cf842fa4c4ba96b3", "question": "On what sea did the \"Battle of Jutland\" take place?", "answer": "North Sea", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5febb7107e83c707845b212e", "question": "What is another word for involuntary muscle twitches?", "answer": "Myoclonus", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3eb", "question": "Who was the prime minister of Canada for the majority of Bill Clinton's time as U.S. President?", "answer": "Jean Chretien", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e36", "question": "What children's classic first chapter is titled \"Mowgli's Brothers\"?", "answer": "The Jungle Book", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "596dfc6d9616e6c6d4eba4f1", "question": "Betsy Ross was born with a fully formed set of what?", "answer": "Teeth", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1c4", "question": "What Italian patriot led the Redshirts?", "answer": "Guiseppe Garibaldi", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be79", "question": "Where are US coins with a \"D\" mark minted?", "answer": "Denver", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5e5f11e3d274615ecf51453c", "question": "\"Oscitation\", is the medical term for what?", "answer": "Yawning", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbab", "question": "What game introduced the characters Raiden, Liu Kang, and Sub-Zero?", "answer": "Mortal Kombat", "category": "general"}, {"id": "597cd809e347d002c297e4c6", "question": "In Greek mythology, who flew too close to the Sun?", "answer": "Icarus", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fefa4f06ce05a3942286eb9", "question": "What is Cat Stevens' birth name?", "answer": "Steven Demetrius Georgiou", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ab99bd521a8909e5c332d30", "question": "What year was the novel \"Who Censored Roger Rabbit?\" published?", "answer": "1981", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0a1", "question": "How many gallons does a Hogshead barrel typically hold?", "answer": "63", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339db9", "question": "How does the hook-handed Woody Harrelson lose his right hand in the film \"Kingpin\"?", "answer": "In a bowling ball return", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a46b", "question": "What is the most northern capital city in Europe?", "answer": "Reyjkavik", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bad6", "question": "In 1996, what became the first minivan to be named Motor Trend magazine's \"Car of the Year\"?", "answer": "Dodge Caravan", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b43", "question": "Taking advantage of a fad at the time, what song became a #1 hit for Ray Stevens in 1974?", "answer": "The Streak", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c37c", "question": "Who developed the classification we use for clouds?", "answer": "Luke Howard", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a05", "question": "What was the first movie adaptation of a Hannibal Lecter novel to feature Anthony Hopkins?", "answer": "The Silence of the Lambs", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133974d", "question": "What is Alecia Moore better known as?", "answer": "P!NK", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe8f22801dd7bf43be5e80d", "question": "What do skydivers traditionally do for their 100th jump?", "answer": "They skydive nude", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133956a", "question": "What was nominated for an outstanding children's program Emmy in 1992?", "answer": "Winne the Pooh and Christmas Too", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5cc", "question": "What cards do you have if you have a \"Big Slick\" in the game \"Texas Hold 'Em\"?", "answer": "An ace and a king of the same suit", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc15", "question": "United Nations' headquarters are located in what city?", "answer": "New York City", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd81d90d0de9af39e9d4690", "question": "Who was the first elected President of the Republic of Texas?", "answer": "Sam Houston", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396d5", "question": "What instrument did Michelle play in American Pie?", "answer": "Flute", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59a1a48612f2a7826b9b8731", "question": "In Greek mythology, Dione was the mother of which goddess?", "answer": "Aphrodite", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf98", "question": "What's the international radio code word for the letter \"V\"?", "answer": "Victor", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5a899bb860d398dc9cf7a6a0", "question": "Which US state is nicknamed the Pelican State?", "answer": "Louisiana", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5cefc0ec948005ec986edce1", "question": "Who is the eighth member of the group LOONA to debut?", "answer": "Choerry", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6a7", "question": "Guadalupe Mountains National Park is located in which US state?", "answer": "Texas", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4b8", "question": "What is the only nation that borders both Belgium and Spain?", "answer": "France", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5a4a978261d1b4d384d5d685", "question": "What is the study of grasses called?", "answer": "Agrostology", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133904e", "question": "Which author wrote the \"Redwall\" series of novels?", "answer": "Brian Jacques", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe8b35301dd7bf43be5e7ac", "question": "What was the first video game played in space?", "answer": "Tetris", "category": "general"}, {"id": "601218b963c99d48cd169af7", "question": "In Swedish, what is \"entrance\" and \"driveway\", respectively?", "answer": "\"Infart\" and \"Uppfart\"", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4fe", "question": "What compound makes up around 60% of the human body weight?", "answer": "Water", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe4ddf206d333868d34d70b", "question": "Which war was concluded by the Treaty of Utrecht?", "answer": "War Of Spanish Succession", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339132", "question": "What year was the second instalment of \"The Faerie Queene\" epic poem published?", "answer": "1596", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ff6685052a821ff76ae8b03", "question": "Around what sea did Jesus call His first apostles?", "answer": "Christ first saw Peter and Andrew close to the Sea of Galilee. He beseeched them to follow Him.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5bbc91f660f0007efaba0e57", "question": "In which US state is it illegial to eat an orange in a bathtub?", "answer": "California", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c276", "question": "What is September's birthstone?", "answer": "Sapphire", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1eb", "question": "Who released the album titled \"The Spaghetti Incident\"?", "answer": "Guns N' Roses", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339697", "question": "What TV family lived at Southfork Ranch?", "answer": "The Ewings", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c282", "question": "What is the largest gland in the human body?", "answer": "The liver", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6015e981fe83fe1f2a824be8", "question": "What French entertainer, activist and secret agent had a pet cheetah named Chiquita?", "answer": "Josephine Baker", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe7ce72877e98cb97778a42", "question": "Which place is dubbed as \"The Salad Bowl of the Philippines\"?", "answer": "Benguet", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b44d", "question": "What world leader was assassinated in Cairo on October 6, 1981?", "answer": "Anwar Sadat", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb53", "question": "How deep is each end zone on a CFL football field?", "answer": "20 yards", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba3c", "question": "What animal is depicted on the flag of Wyoming?", "answer": "Buffalo", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339917", "question": "What daytime soap opera takes place in the fictional town of Salem?", "answer": "Days of Our Lives", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fecdb77ec223966ae8f88f6", "question": "The script for what movie was written during shooting breaks on the set of \"Raiders of the Lost Ark\"?", "answer": "E.T. the Extra-Terrestrial", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "594d04f11a1c922dd1ac649f", "question": "What king was murdered by Macbeth?", "answer": "King Duncan", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59decf64ea2747c8aff16d1e", "question": "Junko Tabei was famous for being the first woman to do what?", "answer": "Reach the summit of Mount Everest", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339768", "question": "What is written on the globe in Scarface's closing scene?", "answer": "The World Is Yours", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b178", "question": "When did the Sydney Opera House officially open its doors to the public?", "answer": "20 October 1973", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fede1366ce05a3942286dc3", "question": "In the 2006 movie \"Flicka,\" what type of animal is Flicka?", "answer": "Horse", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59008fa6cf842fa4c4ba96bf", "question": "In what Australian state would you find the city of Launceston?", "answer": "Tasmania", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fdff5bc1cf6db9ac4808ced", "question": "What city is home to the Spanish Steps?", "answer": "Rome, Italy", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d8e", "question": "What famous rapper's real name is Robert Van Winkle?", "answer": "Vanilla Ice", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb17", "question": "In late 2005, on what internet dating site did Dr. Phil begin writing an advice column for?", "answer": "Match.com", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391ac", "question": "What is Homer Simpson's middle initial?", "answer": "J", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5fe", "question": "Which US state is home to Acadia National Park?", "answer": "Maine", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "590681c6ff9c0647b50a8097", "question": "Under what name did Nintendo re-release the Nintendo Entertainment System in 2016?", "answer": "Nintendo Entertainment System: NES Classic Edition", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133cabd", "question": "What common affliction makes the lens of the eye go opaque?", "answer": "Cataracts", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af1c", "question": "General John J. Pershing was in command of the American troops during what war?", "answer": "World War I", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58f5644233a95c66dc4fe74c", "question": "What was the name of Eddie Murphy's character in the 1984 film \"Beverly Hills Cop\"?", "answer": "Axel Foley", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b331", "question": "In what year did the Vietnam War begin?", "answer": "1955", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be10", "question": "Which one of Strawberry Shortcake's four original toy \"friends\" was a boy?", "answer": "Huckleberry Pie", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f14", "question": "What author created Wonderland?", "answer": "Lewis Carroll", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8b0", "question": "Which company manufactured the B-29 Superfortress aircraft?", "answer": "Boeing", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133984b", "question": "The music duo \"Daft Punk\" consists of which two French musicians?", "answer": "Thomas Bangalter and Guy-Manuel de Homem-Christo", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59008cdfcf842fa4c4ba96a3", "question": "Warsaw is the capital of what country?", "answer": "Poland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fdffd261cf6db9ac4808d09", "question": "Where is the only airport to serve four countries within an hour's drive?", "answer": "Bratislava, Slovakia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a986", "question": "What city named its airport after Charles de Gaulle?", "answer": "Paris", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c446", "question": "How many chromosomes does a chicken have?", "answer": "78", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0d8", "question": "In what year did Michelangelo finish painting the ceiling of the Sistine Chapel?", "answer": "1512", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338dce", "question": "From what language did English borrow the word \"tungsten\"?", "answer": "Swedish", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397e8", "question": "Which boat\u00a0passed through the Sea of\u00a0Green, the Sea of Holes and\u00a0the Sea of Time?", "answer": "The Yellow Submarine", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b808", "question": "What relative does a Russian call \"babushka\"?", "answer": "Grandmother", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bb9e", "question": "In a circus, a funambulist is a what?", "answer": "Tightrope walker", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ad9dcfae748bb36357acddf", "question": "In the original \"Oregon Trail\" game, made in 1971, what were the four infectious diseases that could kill members of your party?", "answer": "Typhoid, Cholera, Measles, Dysentery", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339236", "question": "What is the real first name of rock star Prince?", "answer": "Prince", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59067bb3ff9c0647b50a8067", "question": "What video game console did Microsoft release in August, 2016?", "answer": "Xbox One S", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ab99cd621a8909e5c332d3b", "question": "What is the capita of Corsica?", "answer": "Ajaccio", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c230", "question": "What color is cerulean?", "answer": "Blue", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a04c", "question": "Elvis's \"A Little Less Conversation\" was remixed into a 2002 hit single by which musician?", "answer": "Junkie XL", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a9e94a77ccba3ffe45786d6", "question": "What common term is used to describe a length of 9 inches?", "answer": "A span", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca11", "question": "What is the fear of lice called?", "answer": "Pediculophobia", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133948f", "question": "How long did the 1929 Academy Award ceremony last?", "answer": "15 minutes", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ff9", "question": "In Greek mythology, who hired Daedalus to construct the Labyrinth?", "answer": "King Minos", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a264", "question": "On what TV show did Alanis Morrisette appear in the 1980's?", "answer": "You Can't Do that On Television", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb1e", "question": "What food company is listed on the New York Stock Exchange with the single letter \"K\"?", "answer": "Kellogg's", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339690", "question": "What is the name of King Arthur's sidekick in the 1975 movie \"Monty Python and the Holy Grail\"?", "answer": "Patsy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6de", "question": "Liberty Island is located in the harbor of what US city?", "answer": "New York", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5901d8bd709c1c34536e6ea6", "question": "In what country was the first coin operated slot machine invented?", "answer": "US", "category": "general"}, {"id": "594a63842ebb971c1417fb9a", "question": "Which band released the song \"Proud Mary\" in 1969?", "answer": "Creedence Clearwater Revival", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "592eb148f83302ff91e464a6", "question": "Who played the role of Joanna in the film \"Office Space\"?", "answer": "Jennifer Aniston", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd18b6a29d03ab85b632b31", "question": "Who said, \"If you can't explain it to a six year old, you don't understand it yourself\"?", "answer": "Einstein", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe6a10b20565ad31a57c79f", "question": "Which country created the official marathon length of 26.2 miles?", "answer": "United Kingdom", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb0f", "question": "In what country is Guinness Stout brewed?", "answer": "Ireland", "category": "general"}, {"id": "601de9f76b1208747aa7e9d5", "question": "In the Chinese zodiac, with which of the five elements is the snake associated?", "answer": "Fire -- It points to aggression and dominance.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe733b0eec85e375820b224", "question": "What was Australia's original purpose as a colony?", "answer": "To be a British prison", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe8b27201dd7bf43be5e79d", "question": "What does a \"cusp\" birthday imply about your zodiac?", "answer": "Born between two signs", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390b8", "question": "What is Dr. Zhivago's first name?", "answer": "Yuri", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fecc83eec223966ae8f8890", "question": "After Andy gets assaulted and beaten, who exacts revenge on the one who perpetrated it in the movie \"The Shawshank Redemption\"?", "answer": "Captain Bryon Hadley cripples Bogs, the leader of the group that assaults Andy.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd971fd23c87fd04dd15e4f", "question": "During World War II, what famous company produced propaganda films for the U.S. government?", "answer": "Walt Disney Productions", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac99", "question": "Which of the US Presidents was the first to be born in the 20th century?", "answer": "Lyndon B. Johnson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59e80272de59ea584496fe96", "question": "What river is Liverpool situated on?", "answer": "Mersey", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133afc6", "question": "Whose vice president was Nelson A. Rockefeller?", "answer": "Gerald Ford", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aed5", "question": "In what year was Billy the Kid born?", "answer": "1859", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339493", "question": "What does Phil do for a living in the movie \"Groundhog Day\"?", "answer": "He is a weatherman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe65709ae7e414034b5aed5", "question": "According to Greek mythology, who was the first woman on earth?", "answer": "Pandora", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b15", "question": "In which decade did the \"Peanuts\" comic strip debut?", "answer": "1950s", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a07", "question": "Who was the lead singer of the band Audioslave?", "answer": "Chris Cornell", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7cea1877e98cb97778a44", "question": "Where is the world\u2019s largest known beaver dam?", "answer": "Alberta, Canada", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5a4d99ea08b8581f80b092b8", "question": "What month in 2017 did the United Kingdom begin Brexit Negotiations?", "answer": "March", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfff", "question": "Who is known as \"Big Mama\" in ladies pro golf?", "answer": "JoAnne Carner", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113394dd", "question": "What kind of animals are \"Pinky and the Brain\"?", "answer": "Lab mice", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390a4", "question": "The character Lieutenant Pinkerton appears in what work?", "answer": "Madama Butterfly", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b57d", "question": "What ingredient does the word \"sushi\" refer to?", "answer": "Rice", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c8d", "question": "In the \"Popeye\" comics, on what day would Wimpy gladly pay you for a hamburger?", "answer": "Tuesday", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a378", "question": "What is the capital of Finland?", "answer": "Helsinki", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133920d", "question": "Who designed the Rolling Stones' lips and tongue logo?", "answer": "John Pasche", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8ac", "question": "What canals in the human ear serve as the body's balance organ?", "answer": "The semicircular canals", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b904", "question": "What board game introduced the world to the wonders of pop-o-matic dice?", "answer": "Trouble", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aff8", "question": "What were the first names of explorers, Lewis and Clark?", "answer": "Meriwether and William", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59e3f2a35cb9e8bda6821362", "question": "What year did \"Petra\" become a UNESCO World Heritage Site?", "answer": "1985", "category": "history"}, {"id": "600f721aa9e54d890926f6ea", "question": "In which ocean can you find Australia\u2019s Great Barrier Reef?", "answer": "Pacific -- It is comprised of over 3,000 reef systems and contains over 400 different types of coral and is visible from space.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113394b3", "question": "What city did the Solomons call home in the TV show \"3rd Rock from the Sun\"?", "answer": "Rutherford, Ohio", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133980a", "question": "What opera star sang with John Denver on the album \"Perhaps Love\"?", "answer": "Placido Domingo", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7354beec85e375820b248", "question": "Who said, \u201cThere are a terrible lot of lies going about the world, and the worst of it is that half of them are true.\"?", "answer": "Winston Churchill", "category": "history"}]